Hope Onofe

I am a passionate, goal-driven software engineer with experience building websites and web applications. I am skillful at coming up with real solutions to satisfy client requirements. I am familiar with technologies like ASP.NET Core MVC, and ASP.NETCore Web API, Entity Framework Core, SQL Server, Git, and GitHub. 7, Asajon way, Eti-Osa 106104, Sangotedo, Lagos State, Nigeria, NG. +2347068563859 Email: onofehope107@gmail.com GitHub: https://github.com/Hope-22

EXPERIENCE

Decagon, Edo Tech Park — Software Engineer

March 2022 - Present

- Designed, implemented, refactored and tested codes (C#), following best practices for maintainability, testability, and performance.
- Built projects using ASP. Net Core MVC, and Entity Framework.
- Worked with a team that built projects with Microservice, JavaScript, React, ASP. NET Core Web API and SignalR
- Built projects with .NET and React.
- Worked with project managers, developers, quality assurance, and customers to resolve technical issues.
- Experience with Database Management Systems (SQL and NoSQL) with PostgreSQL, and MySQL. Experience writing Unit and Integration tests.
- Experience with Agile methodologies and principles, in project planning, and execution.

Polaris Bank — .NET Software Engineer (Intern)

August 2022 - November 2022

- Implemented endpoints for Asp .NET core Micro services
- Effectively interpreted documentation to meet business requirements
- Improved and worked on existing codebases and effectively managed software functionalities.
- Worked with a team to develop a finance application.
- Built and deployed several projects/endpoints C#, .NET Framework.
- Experienced with Database Management Systems (SQL, MS SQL)
- Implemented new features to the back-end service

TECHNOLOGIES

- C#
- ASP. NET Core
- ASP. NET MVC
- RESTful API
- Microservices
- HTML 5
- CSS 3
- React
- Bootstrap
- Docker
- EF Core
- SQL Server
- MySQL
- Version Control with Git and GitHub
- Heroku
- MySQL
- Test-Driven Development

Wentors, Lagos — Communication and Growth Strategist.

February 2022 - April 2022

- Responsible for developing and executing growth strategies for the Wentors Community.
- Responsible for designing communication/media tools.
- Developed content for the various Wentors social media accounts.
- Developed and delivered a planned communications program that maximized opportunities to increase the Wentors profile, locally and internationally.
- Responsible for developing, creating, writing, editing, and updating copy, planning layouts, and ensuring consistency in message tone and timeliness of content for the company's digital media as required.

CareerXpress, Lagos - Digital Marketer.

Aug 2020 - Feb 2021

- Responsible for planning digital marketing campaigns, including web, SEO/SEM, email, social media, and display advertising.
- Created content, for content calendars, scheduled posts, and ads on social media platforms for brands.
- Identified trends and insights, and optimize spend and performance based on the senses.
- Created designs using graphic tools and software
 Skills: Digital Marketing · Inbound Marketing ·
 Social Media Marketing · Graphic Design

PROJECTS

Reward - Your - Teacher - Application

The Reward-Your-Teacher product seeks to serve as a link between exceptional teachers and their students.

It allows the students to reach out to teachers, and send money

freely to these teachers in appreciation for their excellent and exemplary work.

It is a Microservice application that contains 3 services.

Namely: User Management Service, Notification Service, and Wallet Service.

Technologies Used: C#, Asp.NET Web API, Entity Framework Core, PostgreSQL, SignalR, JWT Authentication, and Authorization, Pay Stack, Heroku, Git, and GitHub. **Link**: Internal

To-Do List

A web application that models a To-do App using ASP. NET Core MVC, saving members' details in an SQL Server database, and implementing multithreading for heavy-duty operations in the application.

Technologies Used: EF Core, Bootstrap, ASP.NET Core MVC, SQL, and NUnit.

Link: https://github.com/Hope-22/To-Do-Application

Portfolio

A portfolio that shows the collection of projects, skills, and experiences. It features a login/ sign-up section where one as an admin can have access to the dashboard in order to add, delete and update the accomplishments.

Technologies Used - Bootstrap, C#, ASP.NET Core MVC, Entity Framework Core, Identity, SQL Server, GitHub.

Link: http://github.com/Hope-22/Portfolio

Task Management System

ASP.NET Core API that performs CRUD operations in an SQL Server database. CRUD stands for Create, Read, Update and Delete.
Used REST patterns while building the .NET API.

Technologies Used - ASP.NET Core Web API, Entity Framework

Core, SQL Server, Swagger, and GitHub.

Link: https://github.com/Hope-22/ASP.NET-Core-Web-API-CRUD-With-Entity-Framework

EDUCATION

University of Benin — B.Sc. (Ed) September 2012 - October 2016.

Bachelor of Science (Education),

From the University of Benin, Nigeria.